hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is jared
mikerkowski and if we haven't met yet i
help coaches and trainers grow their
businesses to make tens of millions of
dollars online using direct response
marketing and i want to show you how you
can do so as well now i have one of my
clients i've been working with for the
last couple of years joshua giles on
here with me today joshua giles is a
pastor a celebrity trainer to major
league baseball players as well as a
multi six figure and just now very close
to approaching seven figure course
creator and coach online and we're here
today to talk about what's working for
him so it can work for you joshua
welcome to the podcast how are you doing
today um thank you sir i really
appreciate it this is awesome having a
good day how about you i'm having a
great day today i was just out in
phoenix with my mom and
and got to take care of her so that was
awesome so
tell me a little bit about about
yourself what got you into
uh making online trainings and doing
stuff like that because i know that
you've actually been you've been
training for years i we looked at your
baseball stuff
um and i i didn't even know that you had
kind of that
experience talk about that and talk
about how things have changed over the
years from where they were maybe 10
years ago to now
yeah absolutely so um i've always had
and you know a love for
um training to marketing i always i
don't know why i've always been
intrigued even when i was in college
about just the mindset and the
psychology and everything that goes
behind it and i understood that i had
just a natural knack for it not knowing
that i'd actually be doing it years
later and so when i first developed my
baseball training
this was before
um
gosh before smartphones this is before
the first apple iphone i remember i had
a little you know blackberry was the
first thing on the market at that time
and you know everybody was going crazy
for their little tiny you know three
inch blackberry or whatever and um and i
remember um developing um a program and
i'm like i'm like man how do i get this
out there and so as i begin to you know
you pray into it and really get some
instruction you know i went to staples i
printed off little inserts i did little
uh i had a little dvd and cor encoding
to you know cds i was doing my own
audios and putting together this whole
package and and then now i'm like well i
don't how am i going to get it to people
and i had a friend who was in london who
understood more of the tech world at
that time so he was really smart in that
that area and i called him up in london
i said what do i do he says you need a
url i'm like what is a url you know and
so i went and bought a name a domain
called pitchharder.com
not knowing that you know it was
literally at those times in google your
you know your normal search ranking was
a lot easier because the algorithm
hasn't leveled out yet and so when
people typed in how to pitch harder i
was the number one in the world for that
category
and it was crazy so next thing i know he
creates me a little site that has you
know you know movements and flash it was
just not really that good but
order started rolling in and i'm like me
and my wife is fulfilling you know going
to staples every other week i mean it
was crazy times learning like man this
is amazing and then guess what it all
stopped
and i'm like what happened see i didn't
understand about google's algorithms and
their new updates and penguin and panda
and all these things they started coming
up with and then if you didn't keep up
with the current trend you would miss
out on carrying over from the first
season to the next season and so it was
a lesson learned in that area of like
and i have it up here oh awesome one of
your sites right here
there here it is pitch harder
right here about you
i haven't seen that in years this is
over on archive.org anybody can pull up
old sites which is really cool on here
so this is it right yeah that's it yep
awesome that was it right there is the
book i still got it you know here
actually i still pull from that that
thing was amazing very cool
so so what kind of
changed for you since then to now
um just really following the trends of
you know what's working what's the now
what was happening so i got to glean
from a lot of people in palm beach when
i had my gym down there and who were you
know tony robbins lives down there there
was dean graziosi would visit all all
these people would come
um and i got to really pull from you
know not only people that were connected
to them but hearing like what's this and
what's going on there so i was really
loving the aspect of the marketing right
and so i started applying it when i'm in
south florida i didn't know what to do
so again i started applying what i was
learning and then my baseball business
and there started blowing up from a more
of a higher ticket standpoint and then
once i tapped out i'm like okay i need
to learn how to really scale this online
and figure out the systems and processes
frameworks and all of this stuff in
order to take it to the masses and so i
really began to dive into that world and
wanted to you know soak up as much
information as i could
yeah
that's awesome so what are you seeing is
like one of the trends right now that's
working for coaches and trainers if they
if they want to grow their business they
want to get more clients out there what
are some of the stuff that we've been
working on lately oh challenges have
been phenomenal um that right there you
explain what those are yeah so a
challenge on having a you know a three
day or five day
um
basically intensive or speaking on a
topic of uh you know you're pinpointing
a topic you're pinpointing a pain point
you're pinpointing something where
someone can get a quick win
and you're taking them through that
process to show them really shortening
the sales cycle what it would take to
convert a customer and giving them that
quick win that like hey if i can get
this from a free intensive my goodness
what would it be like if i actually went
the next step with that individual and
so it's really wild because you want to
narrow down like you know number one
who's your audience who are you speaking
to what is your who does your you know
resonates with your voice
and begin to develop something around
that and then progress it you know into
an offer and so forth so that there's
congruency to actually see a result so
you can get a return
okay
now
and you also you also have
kids you're a pastor of a church how do
you manage all of this and and get all
of this done that you've been doing
every single day what kind of because i
a lot of people who follow this podcast
one of the biggest reasons that they
they they have an idea they wanna they
wanna be successful with their coaching
with their training but they got so many
responsibilities outside of that that
they find it nearly impossible to even
put anything out there what would you
say to that person yeah i actually
counseled some people this week on that
um and i still practice it i mean you
imagine i'm not at a level to where i
can sit there and say i'm not still
learning these things because you do you
learn to balance throughout all of life
and you have to prioritize you really do
you have to prioritize what you need to
get done because everything is fighting
for your attention everything wherever
you go
you know we're living in a fight for
your attention world and when you look
at it i was actually talking to somebody
about this the other day i said if you
work nine to five that's eight hours if
you sleep eight hours that's 16 hours
you got eight hours to be productive
and that's not counting getting grass
done cleaning the house kids wife
cooking going to i mean you have a
finite little space to do what the
passion that's within you and to
actually get this content out and so you
got to carve it out you have to say i'm
going to dedicate this no matter what
from 7am to 8am whatever it may be i was
literally helping this guy he says man
i'm slammed i've been in you know
selling cars and doing this all day long
and i and i feel i'm falling back and
i'm just getting to the grind i said
well wake up at five in the morning i
said if you're too tired to do it at
night you cannot neglect spending that
hour doing what you know you're called
to do right so you don't experience
frustration because many people will be
doing a thing but they experience
frustration because they know that you
know they don't have the passion toward
that or they're they're not fulfilling
their calling in that arena
and so
it's you got to balance it out you have
to literally if you have to set a timer
like my wife has timers going off all
day long in that house
and it's
little buzzers on her phone to say you
got to do this for a little yeah
absolutely set time aside to you know to
get you know your spiritual life and set
time aside for the kids set time aside
to cook set you know time aside to work
on your products getting uh your
creations out your digital assets
whatever it may be right in that book i
mean you have to do it and if you can do
those little tiny goals what works for
your body is you actually release
chemical hormones that actually make you
happy because you accomplish something
and so setting micro goals will actually
help you get to the bigger goal
and so
you also so here's your website right
here firebrand global
there's your wife right there tell me a
little bit about this i got a question
for you you're on sid roth you've got
some
great programs that we we've been
working on together you put together
what would you recommend to somebody as
well that's like okay i'm balancing what
i know my priorities are
i know that i'm called to impact people
but
what about
money what about making finances
and and where does that come from and
and and
if i just want to make an impact how
does the money fit into that
yeah absolutely what do you say to that
um i guess you know monetizing your
passions your strength i think we're at
a pivotal moment in time that's never
been here before especially you know
covet pushing a lot of people into the
online space um the
the online industry e-learning is it
will be a 200 i think 35 billion dollar
industry in the next three years and so
now is the time if you have that passion
that desire i think it's easier now than
ever before to literally say i've got an
idea i've got a passion and i can profit
within a few days i could do this within
a week i could do that within two weeks
and literally outdo your salary i mean
very quickly because of the strength you
have and see most people don't even know
they're strong in something but they're
constantly hearing people give them
accolades saying man you're so good at
this and my goodness you're you're the
best at you know uh admit administration
i always call you when i have this
problem start recognizing that as you
are
solving a problem if you can solve a
problem there's always going to be
finances
you're going to be able to pull it in
you know
now now what about this what if
somebody's like i want to have an impact
but i don't want to make any money
how would you answer that
well i mean
i don't see why you would want to make
money by having impact at the same time
but
you know
you know if you just want to make an
impact you could still do it because
again the best time is now when it comes
to your ability to reach people from a
digital perspective or whatever it may
be whatever your calls may be
i mean you can reach millions of people
sitting in a room like we're doing right
now you know and it can if that's your
goal you can change people from your
couch if you want to or or but you want
to put the right systems the right
frameworks in place because that gives
you the best visibility to to the
eyeballs for people to actually see what
it is you have to offer
and and i have a lot of followers they
are christians and stuff somebody been
asking like as a pastor what is your
thoughts on a
you know a lot of people are like is it
is it bad to make money from stuff
especially if it's like spiritual
teaching isn't that like selling god
like yeah what is your thoughts on that
yeah so um i hear that a lot and to be
honest with you the bible says that a
workman is worthy of his wages and that
if i sow into your spiritual thing shall
i not reap carnal things that's actually
the word
i mean most people don't even know that
you know and so you sit there and see
and you know even paul was a tent maker
i mean he actually built tents and did
things and and but when you hear that
word saying if i sow into you spiritual
things shall i not reap carnal things
and that a
a not only a minister is to be paid from
the gospel that's what it literally says
that in the bible too but when you go
from the perspective of i see the
mentality there it's like well you're
selling you know god well please walk
into a christian bookstore and just take
a bible off the shelf and say i'm just
taking the bible and don't pay for it
and see what happens
you paid for the bible
you see what i'm saying or walk into
seminary that charges 35 000 a year and
say i'm just gonna attend here for free
you'll be removed very quickly you see
what i'm saying and so it's not the
essence of like okay you're you're you
know prospering off the gospel know what
literally okay
god wants people to prosper all right
god wants to talk about that a little
bit yeah god wants you to prosper god
wants to put you in an arena of
influence see even in the bible it talks
about when the the master gave um the
minors or the talents to the servants
and says now go multiply them he gave a
command of multiplication the servant
who did not multiply was considered
wicked
and slothful
and so imagine this so everything that's
placed within your hands requires
multiplication whether you're at the
lowest level the highest level you must
continually to multiply now the motive
is the difference okay now i will never
charge somebody for prayer i will never
charge somebody for a thus saith the
lord or a prophetic word or or if
someone needs deliverance never but when
it comes to materials or you know what
i've dedicated my life to studying and
learning then yes there is a fee
associated with that which is actually
small compared to paying 35 000 at a
seminary
that's so good that you said that and
here's something else that i want to ask
you
kind of big picture kind of backing up
here from your experience
do you you're a you're a high
performance guy
you're you really are like like thank
you it doesn't take it
a lot to see that when you see the
baseball stuff and what you've done in
in ministry and in business and some of
the people who follow they're like man
they almost feel down on themselves and
lazy because they're like man i don't
have the same energy or the same
drive as joshua does you know what are
some ways as well this might be a
something a lot of people have never
seen on this podcast before
some ways that they could take care of
themselves physically
in their health
mentally to maybe be able to
to sustain
the work that's needed as a coach or as
a trainer so they don't get burnt out
what would you say to that
imagine you have a ferrari and you put
in you know diesel fuel it don't matter
how good the ferrari looks it's going to
break down right and so you've got to
fuel your body with what it takes to
perform at high levels when you look at
i think there was a study that came out
with the top performing ceos and top
performing business people in the world
they had very amazing regimens when it
came to their health to their
supplements all the things that they
take for me knowing that background
literally i don't get up uh you know
every any morning without a handful of
pure vitamins to b12 to minerals to the
things my body
needs to function because there would be
no way my mental capacity could handle
the workload of what i got to do unless
i had that aspect
one of the things that can help your
brain a lot but especially if you're a
thinker which i am my brain is
constantly thinking and formulating you
know
is uh fish oils fish supplements you
know something that good fats that go
into your brain avocados those things
right there can help you know when you
have writer's block or whatever it may
be like man i just don't have the the
energy or the thought process i've been
you know helping kids all day i've been
tending to my husband or my wife
and you need that extra fuel you need to
be able to have the right things pushing
into your body that can help you prolong
that process
and that's an area that you know maybe
you might feel like my listeners here
that you don't have enough time to
do all the things that you want to do it
could be just optimizing your health a
little bit so that you have more energy
to do it i you know in the last year
i've had to do that um i actually found
last year that i i wasn't eating very
well i wasn't doing
enough exercise and i'm not talking like
hours in the gym like i used to do i'm
talking like you know maybe 20 minutes a
day here just to get my body
made that made this much more of a
difference yeah you know eating eating
green vegetables with each meal
versus you know
chick-fil-a or fried food
every you know every other day like it
makes a huge difference and it's cost
effective now here's here's something
else that i would say
i would ask you is
addictions
you know i have
i've talked to some people
how does this
work when you are
building a business
and let's say you have an addiction to
alcohol or
sugar
or or it doesn't have to be even illegal
drugs or anything like that or anything
like that but just something that's an
unhealthy habit in your life
um
how does that affect your mental focus
oh yeah as a coach or trainer and what
would you say to somebody that maybe you
know they're like man i just i can't i
can't
be my best that i know that i can be and
and then i notice that i keep going to
eating the cookies or i notice that i
can go into
having a drink with my friends and then
i and i wake up hungover the next day
what would you say to that person yeah
so um know that you know if you if
you're created as a you know like a car
has eight cylinders or four cylinders if
god has made you a ferrari engine that's
12 cylinders you're only functioning at
four like a little honda i mean you
really can't get much out of your life
so you really need to step back and
analyze one of the things i've always
done with my life is you know weekly as
i step back and i look at everything i'm
doing and say i'm am i being the most
productive i can is there something i
need to trim is there something i need
to deal with the holy spirit lead me
into this aspect of life maybe you need
to work on this area a little bit
because the bible says that god is
always trimming you to bear more fruit
and so you're constantly in a process of
like bearing much fruit that's the whole
emphasis of being here on earth is
having much fruit an aspect to where
people can look at you say man there's
something different about that one what
is it it is god you see
and so if you're dealing with sugar if
you're dealing with cigarettes or you
know caffeine i mean i've dealt with
caffeine to where right i've literally
cried out to god you deliver me and
you're like what do you mean caffeine
it's legal it may be legal but i know
that it almost let me tell you this this
is what's wild it puts almost like a
film over you internally on your your
nervous system to where it's you're
you're
taking in caffeine
and you're forcing your body to produce
hormones that are fight or flight so
you're literally sacrificing anxiety for
energy yeah i mean literally that's what
we're doing we're trading this out you
wonder why we're stressed and our
adrenal glands are burnt out and all
these things are happening so i had to
reduce my caffeine levels i had to
increase juices you see what i'm saying
yeah i remember when you told me it's
crazy all this stuff that changes
everything it's shocking i mean i had i
had sugar last night i went to a movie
i'm like yeah i'm gonna have some sugar
right yeah
anytime i have sugar my next day is
messed up and i'm like good lord i said
imagine people that do this all the time
i don't know how you function i'm just
telling you
it's crazy but if you want to be free
it's simple you ask for help ask god to
help you deliver me i mean it's as
simple as it's not some nine ten step
program literally just be humble ask for
help god will start to put the right uh
pieces in place that will bring freedom
to you because wow people can be set
free from things and you imagine your
production level going through the roof
by just twisting maybe a little bit less
caffeine maybe a little bit more energy
here maybe a little bit better diet all
of these things oh my god i can't
believe i have so much energy this is
amazing i can think clear i can see
clear i can hear clear and then there
will be some of the best moments you
create something and it doesn't have to
be like extreme level like okay i did
like
have to change all these things that's
what i think burns people out sometimes
is they try to like they change
everything in their life a million ways
and then they're like man i can't do it
i can't yeah the body is in shock
right you know you got to do it like
step by step
small changes make the biggest
difference and it helps you
psychologically because you're getting a
quick win so it releases that hormone
says man i'm doing something i'm doing
something yep now i want to ask you
something and i want to honor those that
are still listening to this podcast
because we've talked about a lot of
stuff that i think could trigger people
could maybe they'd be like wow i didn't
think i was going to listen to this
today
what would you say to someone maybe
they're feeling some guilt and shame
about some of this right now yeah
there's no condemnation that person
there's no condemnation in christ jesus
and so the devil is always trying to
condemn you always put you down make you
feel less than he's always attacking
identity and that's what's huge is that
the number one crisis in the world
whether it's christian or secular is
identity people don't know who they are
and you see that in the three to hate
you know i don't want to go into too
much preaching but
into the three temptations of jesus one
of the things the devil said to him was
i'm going to bring you up here why don't
you if you are the son of god cast
yourself down because god's angels will
take care of you he targeted his
identity if you truly are this then do
this and so he's always looking to say
are you really a coach do you really
know what you're talking about you only
have a ged okay you're divorced three
times
you can't do this who's going to listen
to you and that's constantly playing in
your head not realizing that god has
placed something inside of you that is
gold that somebody else is waiting for
your obedience
wow yeah that hit me right now even too
like you know sometimes i i deal with
that in my own life because i'm like
okay i know where i need to be in my
business but i'm not there yet and i'm
like
can i really do the things that god's
called me dude before i'm there and
every time he's like yes you can because
i called you to it yes absolutely
we don't need to be at a certain place
before we can but that's the direction
that we're going and so something i want
to encourage those of you that are
listening to right now like you don't
have to live the perfect life to be
successful as a coach or trainer but
change a few things and and again
spend some time in prayer spend more
time reading the word
spend more time with your family and
prioritize those things and you'll start
to notice that your business will start
to work out much better for you that's
what's been happening in my life i know
joshua will test that as well any final
words or thoughts that you want to
encourage the people that that watch
this you know
most of the people who will listen to my
podcast they're all christians that's
why i said you can preach oh i love it
much as you want which is awesome here
they all know that i'm i'm a christian
too this is really blessed to me today
you got any final thoughts that you want
to share just in closing on this podcast
i'm hearing this right now take radical
action faith without works is dead you
can sit there and get 9 000
confirmations man somebody just
confirmed i'm supposed to do this man
you know i got a prophetic word man this
is that and you still sit back and wait
for it to happen ain't gonna happen you
gotta put some steps in place there's
processes god takes you through
processes i mean he took many people in
the bible through process before they
actually accomplished what they saw in
the future and so the bible says grow
not what weary and well doing but in due
season
you shall reap if you faint not so i
declare over you you shall not faint you
shall come forth in your due season and
may you be encouraged in the mighty name
of jesus
amen that's so good thank you joshua
thank you sir for being here and where
where can they find more information
about you and what you're doing right
now yeah so you can go to
firebrainglobal.org that is our ministry
aspect and you can see many other things
that will you know be in the tabs and
and
future things to come yeah yeah i know
we're updating that site here right now
absolutely it's awesome
awesome plug in with joshua he's got
some amazing training amazing content um
spiritual training uh he's doing some
stuff for for kingdom entrepreneurs here
coming up very soon which is really cool
some of y'all that are listening to this
want to plug into some of that if you
want some good bible teaching and
combine that with your business plug in
with joshua firebrandglobal.com
joshua thank you so much for being here
everybody grow your life if this has
helped you
in any way please share this episode
with other people yes don't keep this to
yourself don't hold it back i know that
you know a friend that this is going to
impact we'll talk soon have a good one
everybody awesome